ROBERT SHETTLEWOOD



CULTURAL RESEARCHER, SOCIAL MEDIA & BRAND MANAGER

CONTACT

1 678 964 1749

rhshettlewood@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/
robertshettlewood/

131 Boerum St, Brooklyn,

NY 11206

EDUCATION

NEW YORK UNIVERSITY

The Silver College of Arts and Science and, 2022 Bachelor of Arts, Psychology

SKILLS

Professional

Time Management Schedule Management Project Planning Presenting

Technical

- -Data Analysis
- -Qualitative Research
- -Communicating through decks
- -Fluent in social media management tools like Sprinklr, Spredfast, Hootsuite.
- -Proficient in Microsoft Word,
- Excel, Tableau and IBM SPSS statistics software

PROFILE

An analytical and creative problem solver, cultural researcher, brand manager, storyteller, foodie, music & comic nerd, and a forever student-at-heart. An organized professional that can still thrive in high-pressure and chaotic work environments. A quick learner with project and brand management experience that will hit the ground running. A creative. An empath. A team-player and a leader.

EXPERIENCE

Social Media Manager, MadeIntheURL, New York, NY, — June 2020- Present

- •Managing all social media channels for the blog through tools like Sprinklr, Spredfast, Hootsuite.
- •Creating social media content rollout calendar including planning, scheduling, and posting across platforms.
- ■Using social analytics tools like Facebook Insights, Crimson Hexagon, Topsy, Netbase and Simply Measured to generate insights.
- Responsible for all creative copywriting across social platforms.
- Building a network of young creatives around the globe through social media outreach.

Trend and Consumer Insights Researcher, Converse, New York, NY — Jan.2021-Nov. 2022

- Worked along side the Director of Consumer Insights as well as analysts from Western Europe and China to provide insights in quarterly macro-trend research presentation that informed and drove brand, social and comm strategy.
- Worked closely with footwear and apparel design teams, delivering insights and easy-to-understand presentations.
- \blacksquare Conducted consumer interviews, leading focus groups, and connecting the brand to underrepresented communities and sub-cultures around NYC.

Campus Brand Manager (Internship), Timberland, New York, NY — July 2021- Jan. 2022

- •Drafted creative pitches and social media captions (and tweets) to captivate a younger, trendier audience.
- Coordinated a social media content schedule and presented social media research based on microcommunities and trends on Tiktok, Instagram, and Twitter. Planned and budgeted campus-wide Timberland events at NYU and used social media and e-mail to optimize brand reach within the oncampus community.
- Created sponsored social media content and tracked KPI to deliver insights.